cancer.net 2018-11-19

# Privacy Policy | Cancer.Net

_Last modified: July 31, 2017_

### Contents

  1. Introduction
  2. Certain General Principles, Terms, and Disclaimers
  3. Who Collects Information Through the Website
  4. Types of Information We Collect and Use When You Visit Our Website
  5. How We Use Your Information
  6. How We Disclose Your Information
  7. Your Rights to View and Correct Information You Provide
  8. Your Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information
  9. How We Secure and Dispose of Your Information
  10. How the Interactive Areas of the Website Operate
  11. The Oncology Career Center™
  12. Children Under the Age of 13 - Compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act
  13. Your California Privacy Rights
  14. Changes to our Privacy Policy
  15. Where You Can Get Questions Answered about the ASCO Privacy Policy
  16. Glossary
  17. International Users

### 1\. Introduction

 **American Society of Clinical Oncology, Inc.** (hereafter “ **ASCO** ,” “ **we** ,” or “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) has worked hard to bring you an informative and user-friendly Website that is sensitive to concerns about privacy.  We have designed this Privacy Policy to explain how and when ASCO collects, uses, and safeguards the information you provide and that we collect through our Website.

By using, accessing, or becoming a Registered User of the Website, you consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy applies to information you provide to us or that we collect automatically:

  * When you visit the Website.
  * Through email, text, and other electronic messages or communications between you and the Website or ASCO.
  * When you interact with Website content or applications that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website and that are provided or managed by a third-party, if that content or application includes a link to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information:

  * We collect offline or through any other means not referred to above; or
  * Collected through our mobile applications, which provide dedicated non-browser based interaction between you and ASCO.  Our mobile applications are governed by a separate Mobile Application Privacy Policy, available when you download each application.

This Privacy Policy will tell you:

  * Who collects information;
  * What types of information are collected and how this is done;
  * How ASCO uses and discloses the information that is collected;
  * Your rights to view and correct information that you voluntarily submit to us;
  * Your rights to opt-out, opt-in, or limit specific uses and disclosures of your information;
  * How ASCO secures your information;
  * How the interactive areas of our websites operate;
  * How we comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act; and
  * Where you can get answers to your questions about this Privacy Policy.

We hope that reading this Privacy Policy gives you a clear idea of how we manage information about you.  Throughout this Privacy Policy, we have underlined various terms and hot-linked them to our Glossary (Section 16 of this Privacy Policy), or hot-linked to a relevant Section within this Privacy Policy, to help you better understand their meaning.

Please carefully review this Privacy Policy to understand our policies and practices regarding the collection, use and treatment of your information. By accessing or using our Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.  This Privacy Policy may change from time to time (see Changes to our Privacy Policy).  Your continued use of the Website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for updates.

### 2\. Certain General Principles, Terms, and Disclaimers

This Privacy Policy does not supersede the Terms of Use that govern your use of the Website.  Any conflict between this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use shall be determined in favor of the Terms of Use.  Please read the Terms of Use carefully, as they are expressly incorporated into this Privacy Policy.

### 3\. Who Collects Information Through the Website

Subject to this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, and any other rules or policies applicable to the Website, ASCO and/or certain third parties collect the information described in this Privacy Policy through the Website. 

#### ASCO Pages and Content Managed by Third Parties

The Website contains Third Party Managed Pages from which third-party vendors may directly collect PII and other information as necessary for completing authorized transactions.

The Website also makes use of third-party Cookies, Web Beacons, Pixels, and dynamic tags, which may allow third parties to collect information about you and your activities on the Website (including Web Information) and provide you, or enable others to provide you, with functionality within our Website or with advertising.  (See Sections 4.a, 5 and 6 for more information.)

#### Links to External Sites.

Our Website provides external links to other websites in order to provide those who use the Website with a better, more fulfilling experience. Once you enter another website (whether through an advertisement, service or content link, sponsorship notice, or otherwise), be aware that ASCO is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of such other sites (see also Section 17 of the Terms of Use). We encourage you to look for and review the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit from our Website.  You should also adjust privacy settings on your Browser or account on any third-party site to match your preferences.

### 4\. Types of Information We Collect When You Visit Our Website

We collect several types of information from and about you when you use or visit our Website, including Personally Identifiable Information (or PII), Non-Personal Information (or NPI), and Web Information, as outlined in this Section.

  *  **a. NPI and Web Information.   **If you use the Website, regardless of whether you are a Registered User, we will collect NPI and Web Information. We collect this information automatically as you navigate through the Website, through our use of automatic data collection technologies including but not limited to first and third-party Cookies, log files, Web Beacons, Pixels, dynamic tag management, and/or through other technical means.  We also collect NPI and Web Information from third parties, such as through third-party advertisements on the Website, from third parties providing services to us, and from third parties with which ASCO advertises.  

Generally, the NPI and Web Information we collect about you is attached to arbitrary system names that are assigned to visitors when they enter the Website.  We may, however, link your NPI or Web Information with your PII in the event that you become a Registered User.  In addition, providers of third-party Cookies, Pixels, Web Beacons, dynamic tags, and/or other technologies used on the Website may have the ability to both link your activities on the Website (including Web Information) with information collected about you elsewhere on the Internet or otherwise in their possession and to use it for their own business purposes, including to provide you with advertising. (See Section 5 for more information on third-party Cookies.)

  *  ** **b. PII.**   **We collect PII directly from you when you provide it to us, such as in the following ways:

    * Information that you provide by filling out forms on our Website. This includes, without limitation, information provided at the time of registering as a Registered User of the Website, updating your registration or profile information, subscribing or unsubscribing to any of our services, registering for meetings, posting material or comments, providing feedback, requesting further information or services, or questionnaires geared towards personalizing content.
    * When you report a problem with our Website.
    * Records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses) when you contact us.
    * Your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes.
    * Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfillment of your orders with us, including account balances and purchasing activity. You may be required to provide information sufficient for us to collect payment for registrations, membership, purchases, subscriptions, or other e-commerce transactions authorized by you, which may include but not be limited to your name, address, email address, credit or debit card information, and other information required to process payment through PayPal or other third-party mechanisms.
    * When you use location-specific searches or directories we provide, such as our ASCO Membership Directory or Find a Cancer Doctor Database.

If you are submitting PII on behalf of others in your family, business or other organization for registration purposes or otherwise, you represent that you have their permission, agreement and full authorization to provide this information to us. We reserve the right (a) to ask you to provide evidence of your authority at any time during, or even after, the submission process and (b) to contact those individuals to confirm your authority at any time. If we determine that your authority has not been properly obtained, we may immediately and without notice to you discontinue your authorized use of those features of the Website for which you have registered.

If you visit the Website through a link from an email newsletter sent by ASCO, our system will log information, including your email address, which links you click through from the e-mail to the Website, the date and time of your click-through, the name of the link or source from which the message was sent, the tracking URL number, and the destination page.

  *  ** **c. Registered Users.   ****Some features on the Website may require you to register as a Registered User and to receive our authorization before you can use those particular features, including forums, mailing lists, meeting registrations, subscriptions, volunteering, abstract submission, manuscript submission, listservs, survey tools, and other services.  In order for you to register and use those features, we may require that you provide us with certain PII and other information about you or your business.  This PII and other information may include names, addresses, e-mail addresses, telephone numbers, fax numbers, education and certifications, areas of specialty, credit card numbers (in relation to certain features), affiliations, research involvement, social media handles, primary professional role, and other forms of PII.  While you may use some of the functionality of the Website without becoming a Registered User, many specific tools and services on the Website require registration and your submission of PII.  The registration process may also include opportunities for you to volunteer additional PII not required for use of the Website, including, without limitation, professional areas of interest, details of past volunteer involvement, demographic information.

Once we have authorized you as a Registered User, we may provide you with a customer identification number and you may be required to select a unique Username and Password. Generally, you will be able to change your Password and update any PII you have given us (instructions on how to make these changes can be found in Section 7 of this Privacy Policy).

If you use Website services or features as a Registered User, you acknowledge and also consent to our tracking of your activities and use of the Website under your Username and/or customer identification number.  ASCO may use such information to improve user experience, in order to confirm and fill orders, maintain quality control and contact you concerning your orders, transactions, or subscriptions,  as well as for other uses consistent with this Privacy Policy.

If you have access to the Website as a designated representative of a business, ASCO may terminate your right to use the Website upon notification that you are no longer a designated representative for that business.

  *  ** **d. Posts to Our Website.** **You also may provide information to be published or displayed (hereinafter, “posted”) on public areas of the Website, or transmitted to other users of the Website or third parties (collectively, “User Contributions”). Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk. Although we limit access to certain pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable.  Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the Website with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed or used by unauthorized persons.

### 5.  How We Use Your Information

We use the information you provide to us and the information we collect automatically to improve our services and your experience with the Website.  Our use of your information and any communications from you to us through the Website will in each case be in a manner consistent with the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy.

#### Use of Your NPI and Web Information

. The NPI and Web Information we automatically collect from you is generally used to render, administer, and improve the Website, our services, and our business. It helps us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service. Purposes for which we may use such information include, but are not limited to, the following: 

  * To present our Website and its contents to you.
  * To help dynamically generate content on web pages or in newsletters.
  * To statistically monitor how many people are using the Website.
  * To track generic user behavior (for example, through Web Information).
  * To monitor how many people open our emails.
  * To help us evaluate the purpose for which our users undertake certain activities, including those listed immediately above.
  * To determine the popularity of certain content.
  * To restrict underage use of our services.
  * To speed up your searches.
  * To enable us and our advertisers and social media partners to display advertisements to appropriate target audience(s) and for other marketing and advertising purposes, including Online Behavioral Advertising.
  * To remember you when you visit the Website, to facilitate your log-in and navigation, and as session timers. To store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests.
  * To locate member practices and practice locations for non-members, to search for members in the ASCO Membership Directory and in our Find a Cancer Doctor Database, to offer institutional licensing, and to comply with location-specific laws through the use of geolocation data.
  * For other commercially reasonable purposes, including measuring advertising and promotional effectiveness and assessing which areas of the Website to remarket to you after you leave our site.

#### Use of Your PII

.  We use PII, and any data that you provide, personal or otherwise, to provide our products and services. Examples of the ways in which we may use PII include but are not limited to the following:

  * To present our Website and its contents to you.
  * To respond to your questions.
  * To remember you when you visit the Website, to facilitate your log-in and navigation, and as session timers. To store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests.
  * To provide you with products, services, or subscriptions you select.
  * To contact you regarding ASCO events or other news.
  * To provide you with information you request.
  * To send and manage surveys.
  * To advise you of products or services that may be available through ASCO.
  * To notify you about Website maintenance, updates, changes, and new features, including products or services we offer or provide through the Website.
  * To notify you regarding your account or subscription, including expiration and renewal notices.
  * To contact you as needed to address a suspected violation of the Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy, or any other rules or policies applicable to the Website.
  * To inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy.
  * To manage membership and volunteer functions.
  * To display content we think may be of interest to you and otherwise help us customize what you see when you visit the Website.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Website.
  * To solicit user feedback to assess user-satisfaction or other needs and interests.
  * To help us in creating new tools, features, and services.
  * To confirm or fulfill purchase and registration requests.
  * To locate member practices and practice locations for non-members, to search for members in the ASCO Membership Directory and in our Find a Cancer Doctor Database, to offer institutional licensing, and to comply with location-specific laws through the use of geolocation data.
  * To enable us and our advertisers to display advertisements to appropriate target audience(s) and for other marketing and advertising purposes, including without limitation through Online Behavioral Advertising and third party social networking sites.
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.
  * In any way we may describe when you provide the information.
  * To render, administer, and improve the Website, our services, and our business in other commercially reasonable ways. 
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

#### E-Commerce Transactions

. When you place an order online with us, register for a conference, pay your dues electronically, or otherwise enter into an e-commerce transaction with us, we collect and transfer to a third-party vendor information sufficient for us to collect payment for and/or fulfill these e-commerce transactions, which may include but not be limited to your name, address, email address, credit or debit card information, and other information required to process payment through PayPal or other third-party mechanisms.

#### Use of Third Party Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

.  The Website makes use of automatic data collection technologies including first and third-party Cookies, log files, Web Beacons, Pixels, dynamic tags, and/or other technical means.  We may use these technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across third party websites or other online services in order to deliver content and advertising tailored to your interests, both on the Website and on third-party websites (including but not limited to search engines and social media websites).  This practice is commonly known as Online Behavioral Advertising. 

The third parties who provide us with third-party Cookies, Web Beacons, Pixels, dynamic tags, and/or other tracking technologies, may use these technologies to collect information about you when you use the Website in order to provide you with advertising based on your visit to the Website. Third parties may have the ability to link the information they collect about you when you use the Website with other information they collect about you elsewhere on the Internet, including but not limited to your PII, NPI, Web Information, or information about the device you are using.  Third parties may also collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services and may use this information to provide you with Online Behavioral Advertising or other targeted content. 

We encourage you to research and learn about Cookies and other technical means, including Web Beacons, Pixels, and dynamic tags, through which information about you may be collected through the websites you visit.  For more information about how to opt out of the use of some of these technologies, see Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information.

#### Social Networking.

ASCO may maintain a presence on third-party social networking sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, and others.  ASCO does not control or have responsibility for the collection, tracking, use, or disclosure of your information (including your PII, NPI and Web Information) gathered through these social networking sites, including through the ASCO pages or profiles within those sites, or otherwise as a result of your participation in social networking sites.  Third-party social networking sites may have the ability to link the information they collect about you when you use the Website with other information they collect about you elsewhere on the Internet, including but not limited to your PII, NPI, Web Information, or information about the device you are using. Third-party social networking sites and advertisers on these sites, including on the ASCO pages or profiles within these sites, are not obligated to follow or apply this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible social networking provider directly.

### 6.  How We Disclose Your Information

#### Disclosure of NPI and Aggregate Information

. ASCO may provide without restriction any NPI, Web Information, or Aggregate Information about our users and information that does not itself identify any individual to third parties. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of users of the Website and the activities they conduct while on the Website. We might, for example inform a pharmaceutical company (that may or may not be a sponsor of the Website), that “30% of our users live east of the Mississippi” or that “25% of our users have tried alternative medicine.”

#### Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information

. We may disclose PII that we collect or that you provide as described in this Privacy Policy:

  * To our subsidiaries and corporate affiliates, including the Conquer Cancer Foundation ([www.conquer.org](http://www.conquer.org/)), CancerLinQ LLC ([www.cancerlinq.com](http://www.cancerlinq.com/)), and QOPI Certification Program, LLC ([http://www.instituteforquality.org](http://www.instituteforquality.org/)).
  * To contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use to support our business, internal functions, products, or services, including but not limited to managing mailing lists, packaging, mailing and delivering purchases and promotional offers, consulting services, data modeling, printing, sending postal mail, outreach efforts, and processing event registrations.
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. For example, to complete transactions you undertake on the Website.
  * To other ASCO Members if you choose to participate in our membership directories (the information made available in directories will include contact information and will not include financial information, such as credit card or bank information).
  * If you are a medical provider and you elect to participate in the Find A Cancer Doctor Database (www.cancer.net/find-cancer-doctor) and authorize the disclosure of your contact information through that Database, or if you are an ASCO Member, your contact information may be disclosed to members of the public accessing that Database.  You may elect to make your information private or cease participation in the Database at any time by contacting ASCO Customer Service (<https://www.asco.org/contact-us>).
  * To our advertising and social media partners, to enable us and our partners to provide advertisements to appropriate target audiences.
  * To private entities and law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate (a) to investigate or resolve possible problems or inquiries, (b) to conform to legal requirements or comply with any court order, law or legal process, including responding to any government or regulatory request, (c) to protect our own rights, property or safety of ASCO, our customers, or others, (d) to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and any other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes, or (d) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. 
  * For any other purpose(s) disclosed by us when you provide the information.
  * With your consent.

Please note that additional disclosure rules apply to information obtained by ASCO through the Oncology Career Center™, which is discussed further in Section 10.

In the event of a change of control of ASCO (or the Website or any portion thereof), such as through a merger, sale, consolidation, transfer of substantial assets, reorganization or liquidation, or other similar transaction, ASCO reserves the right to transfer, sell, or assign to third parties any information we have collected. 

#### Disclosure of Information to Third-Party Vendors and Service Providers

.  ASCO has engaged third-party vendors and service providers to provide services in connection with the Website, outreach for our programs and services, and to help us manage our web presence and allow us to better serve our users.  In addition, some of the content and services on the Website, including advertisements, are served by third parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and technology and application providers.  We may share PII or other information with these third-party vendors and service providers as necessary so that they may provide the services for which they have been engaged.  PII and other information submitted to ASCO through Third Party Managed Pages are also shared with the relevant third-party vendor as necessary for completing authorized transactions.

### 7\. Your Rights to View and Correct Information You Provide to Us

If you are a Registered User of the Website, you can review, correct and change your PII (and any preferences) by logging into the Website and visiting your account profile page.

You may also send us an email at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org) to request access to, correct, or delete any PIIthat you have provided to us.  We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.  If you withdraw your registration as a Registered User of the Website we may retain your PII in our records and we may continue to use and disclose that data in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, unless you request deletion of it.

If you delete your User Contributions from the Website, copies of your User Contributions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Website users.  Please refer to our Terms of Use for information relating to the proper access and use of User Contributions.

### 8\. Your Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information

You are able to control your information in the following ways:

#### Promotional Offers from ASCO and Third Parties

. When you register, you may be asked whether you want to receive special announcements and future newsletters by email. If you check “yes” but change your mind at any time in the future and no longer wish to receive our newsletter and other special announcements by email, you will be able to Opt-Out of these services by: (a) going to your ASCO.org profile and selecting “Manage Email Subscription,” (b) using the Email Subscriptions link within an e-mail to access our preference center, and selecting “Update”; (c) following the directions included at the bottom of any newsletter issue; and/or (d) sending us an email at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org), and we will take you off the applicable email list.  You may also Opt-In to receive email communications from us and trusted third parties at the point of registration or by similarly following the instructions above.  This Opt-Out does not apply to information provided to us as a result of a product or service purchase, product service communications, or other transactions.

#### Cookies

. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser Cookies, delete Cookies after a time, or to alert you when Cookies are being sent.  Your Browser can be set to reject all Cookies and you can clear Cookies at any time. A “help” section of most Browsers’ toolbars usually offers instructions on how to reset the browser to reject Cookies. To learn how you can manage your Flash Cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings on Adobe’s website.  If you disable or refuse Cookies, please note that some parts of the Website may not function properly, or may no longer be accessible.  Various third parties provide additional tools to assist you in managing your own preferences regarding Cookies and Online Behavioral Advertising.

### 9\. How We Secure and Dispose of Your Information

ASCO has implemented reasonable security measures designed to secure your PII from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. Access to data and technology relating to user information is password-protected and limited to authorized personnel and those vendors that require access to the information in order to furnish services to ASCO and our members. In addition, ASCO uses industry standard technology to keep users’ information secure while residing on ASCO’s servers.  However, despite these measures, our IT systems could be compromised by parties seeking unauthorized access to our data or users’ data, by a technological malfunction or by an error by an employee, vendor or contractor.  In addition, the transmission of information via the Internet could be intercepted by third parties.  As a result, our efforts to protect our data and users’ data from unauthorized access may be unsuccessful and we cannot assure you that the security measures we have adopted will provide absolute certainty.  By using, accessing or become a Registered User of the Website, you agree that ASCO is not responsible or liable for any loss or damage of any sort arising from or relating to any breach of our security, circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures, or interception of your transmissions (see Terms of Use).  Any transmission by you or use of our Website is at your own risk.

When you provide PII and credit card information for e-commerce transactions, this information is encrypted using industry-standard SSL Encryption technology before being sent over the Internet.  We submit to the appropriate credit card clearinghouse only the information necessary to collect payment. All credit card information retained by ASCO, including credit card numbers if you elect to store them on your account, is compliant with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you.  Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Website like message boards.  The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Website.

Information related to your ASCO membership will be retained unless you contact us at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org) to request its deletion.  Other information you provide to us and that we collect from you will be retained for no longer than reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was obtained, or for a period specifically required by law or regulation.  Your information will be disposed of in a manner that seeks to prevent loss, theft, misuse, or unauthorized access. 

### 10.  How the Interactive Areas of the Website Operate

As a service to our users, the Website may feature message boards, chat rooms, listservs, and/or other public forums where users can share information or where users can post questions. We may also offer online discussions moderated by medical or healthcare experts.

In addition, you may choose to use certain interactive content, tools, and services that ask you to voluntarily provide information about yourself. Some of these tools (like certain quizzes or calculators) do not retain information, while others may store information in accordance with the authorization you provide at the time you use the service or tool. Please be aware of this fact.

Any chat room, message board, forum or similar interactive service is by design open to the public and is not a private, secure service. ASCO is not responsible for the privacy of information voluntarily provided by a user in interactive areas. You should think carefully before disclosing any PII in any public forum because what you have written may be seen, disclosed to, or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict, including to contact you for purposes unauthorized by you.

### 11\. The Oncology Career Center™

Because the Oncology Career Center™ ([careercenter.asco.org](http://careercenter.asco.org/)) is a career site, it gives job seekers the option of posting their resumes to our database. There are two ways to post a resume.

#### Non-Searchable Submission

. You can store your resume in our database, but elect during the registration process to exclude your resume from searches by potential employers. Excluding your resume from database searches means that you can use it to apply for and respond to individual job postings, but employers will not have the ability to search for it.

#### Searchable Submission

. During the registration process you will have the option to allow your resume to be searchable by potential employers. Selecting this option permits all parties with access to our searchable resume database to have access to your resume.

You may remove your resume from the database, and change the status of the resume from searchable to non-searchable, and vice-versa, at any time by updating your profile page on the Oncology Career Center™. 

Please note that the Oncology Career Center™ is an interactive service that uses Cookies and tracking technologies, subject to the policies and disclaimers in Section 5 of this Privacy Policy and in the Terms of Use. We cannot and do not guarantee that third parties will not, without our or your consent, gain access to our resume database. You hereby expressly (a) acknowledge that registered employers and other third parties who gain access to the database with or without our or your consent may retain a copy of your resume in their own files or databases, even if you subsequently change the status of your resume to non-searchable, and (b) agree that in no event shall ASCO be responsible or liable for the retention, use, duplication, distribution, or privacy of resumes in these instances.

### 12\. Children Under the Age of 13 - Compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age.  No one under age 13 may provide any PII to or on our Website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org).

### 13\. Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of our Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, please send us an email to privacy@asco.org or write us at American Society of Clinical Oncology, Inc., 2318 Mill Road, Suite 800, Alexandria, Virginia 22312, Attn: Privacy Officer.

#### California Do Not Track Disclosure

. ASCO does not have a mechanism in place for responding to browser “do not track” signals or other similar mechanisms used to limit collection of information for use in Online Behavioral Advertising.

### 14.  Changes to our Privacy Policy

ASCO reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time by posting revised terms directly to this page.  Amendments to this Privacy Policy are effective when posted and the date on which the Privacy Policy was last revised is identified at the top of this page.  ASCO does not have an obligation to provide further notice of any changes and it is each user’s responsibility to monitor and review updates to this Privacy Policy.  If we make material changes to how we treat our users’ PII, we will notify you by email to the primary email address specified in your account, to the extent you are a Registered User with us and provided a deliverable email address.  You are responsible for ensuring that we have an up-to-date, active and deliverable email address for you.  Your continued use of the Website after the posting of amendments will be deemed acceptance of the changes to the Privacy Policy.

### 15\. Where You Can Obtain Answers about the ASCO Privacy Policy

If you have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy and our privacy practices, please contact: [privacy@asco.org](mailto:privacy@asco.org). If you do not receive adequate resolution of a privacy related problem, you may write to ASCO at: 2318 Mill Road, Suite 800, Alexandria, VA 22314, Attention: Chief Legal Officer.

### 16\. Glossary

**Aggregate Information**. Non-Personal Information, Web Information, or Personally Identifiable Information that has been de-identified and that is combined with similar data related to more than one individual to form aggregated information.  For example, the site may add up the total number of people in Peoria, Illinois (but not their names) who are seeking information about pancreatic cancer and compare that to the number of people in Petaluma, California seeking the same information.  This sort of statistical information is called Aggregate Information because it reflects the habits and characteristics of an anonymous group of people. Websites may use aggregate data or share it with third parties so that the information and services provided best meet the needs of their users. Aggregate Information also helps advertisers and sponsors on the Website know how effectively they are reaching and meeting the needs of their target audience.

**Browser**. Short for web browser, a browser is a software application used to locate and display pages of the Internet. Popular browsers include Mozilla Firefox, Microsoft Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Opera, and Apple Safari. Most modern browsers can present multimedia information, including sound and video, though they require plug-ins for some formats.

**Cookie (or browser cookie)**. A small data file that is stored on the computer you use to view a website. Cookies are placed by that site (“ **first party** ”) or by a third party with a presence on the site (“ **third party** ”), such as an advertiser using a Web Beacon, and are generally accessed only by the party or site that placed the Cookie on the computer (i.e. a Cookie placed on your computer by ASCO is generally not accessed by any other site you visit but a Cookie placed on your computer by an advertiser may be accessed by any site on which that same advertiser has a presence). Cookies can contain pieces of Personally Identifiable Information. Cookies often are used to make the site easier to use. For example, if you check a box to ask that we store your Username on your computer so that you don’t have to enter it each time you visit the site, that information is stored in a Cookie on your computer.  Cookies may be persistent (meaning that they are saved on your computer even after you close your Browser and may be accessed at a later time) or non-persistent (meaning that they are deleted when you close your Browser). Cookies may be “essential” for the use of a website, such as for example session-id cookies, authentication cookies, or user centric security cookies, or “non-essential” for the use of a website, such as for example, third party advertising cookies or other tracking cookies.

**Encryption**. The translation of data into a secret code. Encryption is one way to achieve data security. To read an encrypted file, you must have access to a secret key or Password that enables you to decrypt it. This is typically done by so called “secure computer systems.”

**Non-Personal Information (“NPI”)**. Information that may relate to an individual but does not by itself identify that individual. For example, Web Information is Non-Personal Information, as is information such as gender, age, city, and physical location, when not linked with other Personally Identifiable Information.  NPI may be “re-identified” through certain processes by linking it to PII relating to the same individual.

**Online Behavioral Advertising**.  The practice of using online tracking technologies such as Cookies and Web Beacons to collect information, including Web Information, about a user’s online activities over time and/or across third-party websites or other online services in order to deliver advertising and content tailored to the user’s apparent interests.

**Opt-In**. An option that allows you to actively indicate your preference to participate in a program, email, feature, tool, or enhancement on a website. Typically, if you “Opt-in” you must provide certain information, usually Personally Identifiable Information, to the website or otherwise actively indicate your choice or preference to participate in the website program. For example, if you wish to receive a newsletter by email from the _Journal of Clinical Oncology_ ([jco.ascopubs.org](http://jco.ascopubs.org/)), you can enter your email address and choose the type of newsletter by checking a box next to a statement such as: “Yes, I’d like to receive the JCO Newsletters.”

**Opt-Out**. An option that allows you to actively indicate your preference not to participate in a program, email, feature, tool, or enhancement on a website. Typically, if you “Opt-Out” you must uncheck a box next to a stated preference or otherwise take some action to indicate your preference not to participate in a program. Failure to opt-out typically means that you will, by default, participate in the program, feature, tool or enhancement.

 **Password**. A secret series of characters, typically alphanumeric (meaning it consists of both letters and numbers), that enables a user to access a file, computer, or program. The user must enter its, his, or her password before the computer or system will respond to commands. The password helps ensure that unauthorized users do not access the system. In addition, data files and programs may require a password. A password should be something that nobody but the user could guess.

**Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”)**.  Information that identifies or is uniquely associated with an individual, such as a name, tax payer identification number, home address, telephone number, email address, Social Security number, or credit card number.

 **Pixel.  **See the definition of “Web Beacons”.

**Posted.**   Defined in Section 4.d of this Privacy Policy.

**Registered User.  **Users who register to use particular features of the Website that require registration and, in some instances, the submission of PII, including but not limited to forums, mailing lists, meeting registrations, subscriptions, and other services, as described in Section 4.c of this Privacy Policy.

**Server**. A computer that provides services to other computers. A “web server” stores web site files and “serves” them to people who request them.  Servers may belong to ASCO or to other affiliated or non-affiliated entities.

**SSL (Secure Sockets Layer)**. A security protocol developed by Netscape for transmitting private information via the Internet. SSL works by using a private key to encrypt data that’s transferred over the SSL connection. All major Browsers, including Microsoft Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, Opera, and Apple Safari, support SSL, and many websites use the protocol to transmit confidential user information, such as credit card numbers. By convention, URLs that utilize an SSL connection start with https: instead of http:.

**Third Party Managed Pages**.  Certain pages of the website, such as registration, job search, journal, and submission pages that are managed by third parties, and from which third party vendors may directly collect PII and other information as necessary for completing authorized transactions, including but not limited to websites for ASCO’s publications such as the _Journal of Clinical Oncology,_ the _Journal of Oncology Practice, the Journal of Global Oncology, JCO: Clinical Cancer Informatics,_ and _JCO: Precision Oncology_ ([ascopubs.org](http://ascopubs.org/)), the Oncology Career Center™ website ([careercenter.asco.org](http://careercenter.asco.org/)), portions of the Career Opportunities at ASCO page ([www.asco.org/about-asco/careers-asco](http://www.asco.org/about-asco/careers-asco)), portions of ASCO in Action ([ascoaction.asco.org](http://ascoaction.asco.org/)), the Conquer Cancer Foundation Donation page, the TAPUR page, the QOPI page, the Cohort site, the PracticeNET participation page, abstract submission, meeting or conference registration, voting, and shopping cart pages, the ASCO ACT Network (<http://cqrcengage.com/asco/?0>), and the ASCO State/Regional Affiliate Program page ([myaffiliates.asco.org](http://myaffiliates.asco.org/)).

**Username**. A name used to gain access to a computer system or program. Usernames, and often Passwords, are required in shared systems, such as the Internet. In most such systems, users can choose their own usernames and passwords.

**User Contributions**.  Defined in Section 4.d of this Privacy Policy.

**Web Beacons** or **Pixels** (also often referred to as “clear GIFs,” “pixel tags,” “1-by-1 GIFs,” “Single-Pixel GIFs,” “1 x 1 Pixels” or “clear Pixels”).  Pages of the Website and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons that permit us and/or third parties to collect Web Information during your visit to the Website.  For example, Web Beacons may be used to count the number of users who have visited a page or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity). Web Beacons send information back to their home Server (which can belong to the host site, a network advertiser, or some other third party) from the users’ Browser, such as the IP address, the URL of the page on which the beacon is located, the type of Browser that is accessing the site, and information stored in any Cookies on the users’ computer previously placed by that Server. Web Beacons can also be used to place a Cookie on the users’ Browser.  Third parties who provide us with web beacons or pixels may have the ability to link the information they collect about you when you use the Website with other information they collect about you elsewhere on the Internet, including but not limited to your PII or information about the device you are using.

**Web Information**.  Information about your activities on the Website and the technology you use to access the Website, including information about the date and time you visit the Website, the services you accessed from the site or from an email, how you arrive at the Website (through referral or exit links or otherwise), which pages you view, any files you download, for how long you visit the Website and view pages, when you last visited the site, your IP address, your location, your connection, your search terms, the type of Browserand operating system you use, mobile device make and model, mobile device carrier information, and mobile device support specifications such as screen size, color, video, and image support.

**Website**.  Collectively, the ASCO website ([www.asco.org](http://www.asco.org/)), the Cancer.Net website ([www.cancer.net](http://www.cancer.net/)), the __ ASCO Journals websites __ ([ascopubs.org](http://ascopubs.org/)), the Oncology Career Center™ website ([careercenter.asco.org](http://careercenter.asco.org/)), the Quality Oncology Practice Initiative website ([http://www.instituteforquality.org](http://www.instituteforquality.org/)),  Oncology Practice Central ([oncologypracticecentral.asco.org](http://oncologypracticecentral.asco.org/)), the ASCO University website ([university.asco.org](http://university.asco.org/)), the ASCO Connection website ([www.connection.asco.org](http://www.connection.asco.org/)), the ASCO Photo Gallery ([photos.asco.org](http://photos.asco.org/)), the TAPUR Study website ([www.tapur.org](http://www.tapur.org/)), the ASCO University Meeting Library website ([www.meetinglibrary.asco.org](http://www.meetinglibrary.asco.org/)), the ASCO in Action website ([www.ascoaction.asco.org](http://www.ascoaction.asco.org/)), the ASCO Volunteer Portal ([volunteer.asco.org](http://volunteer.asco.org/)), certain state affiliate websites ([myaffiliates.asco.org](http://myaffiliates.asco.org/)), meeting microsites, and any other online functionalities or services included in the websites operated by ASCO, but excluding our mobile applications, or “apps.”

### 17\. International Users.

ASCO and the Website is based in the United States and, regardless of where you access the Website, the information collected as part of that use will be transferred to and maintained on servers located in the United States.  Any information we obtain about you will be stored in accordance with U.S. privacy laws, regulations, and standards, which may not be equivalent to the laws in your country of residence. By using the Website, you consent to this collection, transfer, storage, and processing of information to and in the United States in accordance with the foregoing.
